# Miracle Friday

F.C.T. Abuja, Nigeria +234 9081146028 miraclef60@gmail.com

Full-stack developer experienced with developing web apps/mobile apps (front-end) and API (back-end) infrastructure, also experienced with distributed systems with docker containers and AWS services. With over 6+ years of experience in software development, deployed and launched 2 mobile applications currently on the google play store, and worked with various local startups to launch fast growing platforms of a combined more than 3000 monthly active users.

# **Work Experience**

# Flutter Mobile App Developer

04/2020 to 09/2022

Convexity Technologies Lmtd (chats.cash)

F.C.T. Abuja, Nigeria

- I was responsible for developing a set of mobile apps for the solution known as CHATS, that aims to distribute cash vouchers through the blockchain technology.
- Overhauled legacy source code of two mobile applications that where in development to increase their performance speeds by 64%
- Pointed out issues in which the user experience was lacking and required upgrades, resulting in a 15% increased usability
- Well documented application of design patterns in use making code base 4 times easier to maintain or update a
  feature, which led to 10% increased speed from development to deployment to the app store
- Instrumented suggestions to greatly reduce redundancy and turn up of bugs in CI/CD pipeline

# Frontend Developer

05/2022 to 09/2022

Sonergy (sonergy.io)

F.C.T. Abuja, Nigeria

- Took on the responsibility for building the web UI and consuming available REST API endpoints t drive the functionality of the web app, also integrated web 3.0 functionality by communicating with deployed smart contracts, on the BSC network
- Revamped user journey leading to 20% faster time to deployment and launch
- Identified key areas that might put off users, with system wide changes leading 5x user retention on the platform
- Implementation of automated unit and integration tests leading to an increased efficiency in writing and debugging the code base

#### **Fullstack Developer**

02/2021 to 03/2022

WrappedCBDC (wrapcbdc.com)

# F.C.T. Abuja, Nigeria

- Took on the role of building both back-end (REST API) and front-end infrastructure for the project as well integrate web 3.0 features
- Designed and architected the entire platform systems, as well as making key decisions on technologies to be used
- · Adopted core design principles increasing the speed and efficiency of collaboration, on the team by 20%
- Managed cross-functional team of 4 in 2 locations, ranging from designer to junior level developers and blockchain developers
- Pitched solutions to key problems plaguing the idea to stakeholders that where implemented leading to 32% more adoption of the platform by major industry players
- · Worked with major stakeholders in the industry

# Skills

JavaScript/TypeScript - 6 years

NodeJS - 5 years

ReactJS - 4 years

ExpressJS - 4 years

Backend Development - 4 years

Frontend Development - 4 years

Flutter/Dart - 3 years

Mobile Application Development - 3 years

Android/iOS Application Development - 3 years

Rust programming language - 2 years

Systems architecting - 2 years

Domain Drive Design - 2 years

# **Education**

# **Hill City University Benin**

Bachelor's Computer Science Cotonou, Republic of Benin 03/2019 to 08/2021